Jude Lim (Ken Yoong)

MS in Computer Science and Applications

Email:

lkyoong428@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jude-lim

-9a2612101/

Mobile:

Location:

+1703-679-0990

Github: https://github.com/KenLim4337/

+1703-679-0990

Portfolio:

Falls Church, VA

https://kenlim4337.github.io/

I am a master's student in Computer Science and Applications at Virginia Tech focusing on Human Computer Interaction, Data Analytics, and Machine Learning. My passion is developing and designing interfaces that bridge the gap between users and the complex data and software that drive modern systems.

Previously, I earned my undergraduate degree in Information Technology with Honors at the University of Queensland and was also able to learn various skills related to software design, development, and project management. I also have over 3 years of work experience in a variety of roles ranging from front-end development to teaching in coding camps.

With a well-developed skill set centered around web technologies and UX, I am looking for exciting opportunities to further grow as a developer, data scientist, and UX practitioner.

Skills

Hard Skills

Front End Web Development, Conversion Rate Optimization, User Acceptance Testing, A/B Testing, Web Analytics, Back End Web Development, User Experience

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Problem Solving, Attention to Detail, Critical Thinking, Written and Verbal Communication, Adaptability

Technologies

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, Javascript, jQuery, React, Django, PHP

Data and Analytics: MySQL, PostgreSQL, R, Python, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager

Design Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Invision, Figma, Balsamiq, Miro

Other Programming Languages: Java, C#, C, Python

Version Control: Git, Subversion

Languages

English (Native), Mandarin (Intermediate), Cantonese (Intermediate), Bahasa Melayu (Intermediate)

Professional Experience

Conversion Rate Optimization Developer (February 2018 - July 2021)

Conversion Kings (Australia)

Increased conversion rates and revenue for over 40 national and international brands through the development, maintenance and analysis of over 250 A/B tests and web-pages.

- Developed pixel-perfect, responsive, cross-browser A/B tests and web-pages based on prototypes provided by designers.
- Reduced project turnaround time and missed bugs by 30% within the first half-year by implementing a standardized user acceptance testing process and managing the team surrounding it.

Freelance Web Developer (March 2020 - May 2020)

Dance Sydney (Australia)

Designed and developed a cross-browser, fully responsive video player used to deliver online dance courses to users.

Freelance Web Developer (November 2017)

Gliding Queensland (Australia)

Streamlined the website redesign process by fixing existing issues and compiling recommended updates based on user experience principles.

Documented website functions to help existing members easily access and modify published content.

Teaching Assistant (April 2017 - October 2017)

Code Camp (Australia)

Cooperated with other team members to deliver engaging and organized coding lessons to primary school children.

• Lessons were delivered on-schedule and well-received by both children and parents.

Intern (December 2015 - February 2016)

KPerak Implementation and Coordination Corporation (Malaysia)

Delivered a full-stack project in the form of an internal employee assessment web application.

• Project completed 2 weeks ahead of schedule and subsequently deployed with minimal rework.

Volunteer Experience

Hacker & Crew (July 2017)

GovHack 2017 (Australia)

Received honorable mention for the "Going places" national award category by developing a mobile web application.

- Application developed through the usage of various publicly available datasets.
- Made sure participants were hacking in a safe and comfortable environment by helping set up the event location, providing technical support and preparing meals.

Volunteer (March 2017 - November 2017)

Gliding Queensland (Australia)

Constructed a framework for the client's redesign efforts by providing feedback based on design and development best practices.

• Client was very positive toward the work delivered and at the end of the year, received a short term contract to further aid the redesign.

Hacker (July 2016)

GovHack 2016 (Australia)

Won runner-up for the "Evacuation - help us get away!" state award category through collaborating with other participants to ideate and produce a mobile web application using publicly available datasets.

Volunteer (March 2016)

Coder Dojo Brisbane (Australia)

Along with other team members, taught high school students various coding basics and principles.

• Lessons delivered on schedule and effectively with positive receptions from both students and parents.

Education & Training

2021 - Current

Master of Science in Computer Science and Applications, Virginia Tech Graduate Certificate in Data Analytics, Virginia Tech

2019

15.071x The Analytics Edge, MITx on edX

2017

Bachelor of Information Technology (Honours), University of Queensland

2014 - 2016

Bachelor of Information Technology, University of Queensland

Hobbies and Interests

Cooking, Reading, Electronics